COVER LETTER

This is writing to connection with you regarding job vacancy for the post of QC Welding/Coating Inspector. I have More than 8 years of experience in Oil and Gas field in piping Inspection, welding inspection, refinery maintenance/shutdown/turn around and construction projects, NDE inspection, interpretation of radiographs. Provided services to wide range of client from different Projects in the Middle East and holding Saudi Aramco Approval for Many Projects with Saudi Aramco Personnel no (SAP-70015673)

I would like to get your consider to evaluate my CV in attachements. As you can see from my CV I have completed following Degree and certifications,

- Diploma in Electrical and Electronics Engineering
- American Certified Welding Inspector AWS-CWI. certificate No: 09045381
- NACE- 2 Coating Inspector. certificate No: 47363
- ASNT Level 2 (RT,UT,PT,MT)

I have also demonstrated my skills and ability to interact well with others. I believe I would be a valuable addition to your team. I would appreciate of an interview at your convenience. Thank you for your cooperation and I hope to hear from you shortly

I will be available immediately and would like to join anytime if I selected.

Thank you in advance.

Thank and regards N. Srinuvasan India +966537812787(Saudi Arabia)

RESUME

Srinuvasan Natarajan

Anandha Vinayagar Koil street,Kurinjipadi 607302,Cuddalore.dt TamilNadu,India. Cell:+966537812787 Srinivasnatraj.sam@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Experienced QC Coating and Welding Inspector with certification from NACE, American Welding Society. Exhibits strong attention to detail in inspecting coating and welding qualities. Comes with a Diploma in Electrical and Electronics Engineering with 8 years of practical experience.

Be a Professional Inspector that capable to carrying out all inspector duties and maintain Quality Cultural, commitment, and professional will continues to develop itself to create a great vocation & prosperity for qualified resources. If you asking me about quality and I'll say it "QUALITY IS NOT COMPROMISE!" That is all about.

Core Qualifications

- Strong computer and mathematics skills
- Proficient in interpretation of engineering documents and drawings
- Excellent written and oral communication skills
- · Experienced at testing welds and coating at various stages to ensure they meet quality measures
- Utilizes testing methods for Coating to ensure Quality
- Organized and analytically minded

Educational & Professional Qualification

Diploma in Electrical and Electronics Engineering,2006
NACE level-2 Certified on ,2013 Certification ID:47363(Valid Up to 2019)
American Certified Welding Inspector certified on 2009, Certification ID:09045381(Valid Up to 2018)
American Society for Non-Destructive testing, Certified on 2009 (Valid Up to 2018)

Experience

QC Coating Inspector Petrofac Int Ltd Sep,2015-Present Saudi Arabia, KSA. Petrofac

- Ensuring quality by monitoring incoming, in-process and final inspection of procedures, records & ISO documentations
- Monitoring work in progress for compliance with the latest approved revisions of drawings and specifications and verifying that finished work meets acceptance criteria
- · Reviewing painting specifications, technical & safety data sheets, blasting and painting procedures
- Monitoring and verifying blasting and painting quality issues i.e. measuring weather conditions, surface profile, paint thickness, holiday detection test to ensure compliance with relevant project specification
- Ensuring the right time interval between blast cleaning and coating application as per the environmental conditions.
- After completed joint application visual check for continuous and uniform film, free of blisters, sags, runs or color striations.

QC Coating Inspector Saipem, Snamprogetti

Feb,2014-Aug,2015 Saudi Arabia, KSA.



SRINUVASAN NATARAJAN QA/QC WELDING &COATING INSPECTOR

- Quality control of surface preparation and coating together with Painting representative and Owner representatives.
- Responsible for all painting inspection. Check at all stages the proper application of contract specification and the reapproved procedures related to the applied coating system.
- Witness Holiday Detection test for internal coated piping/tanks, pipelines external and underground piping.
- Monitoring and Inspection surface preparation Blasting and Painting to ensure and check abrasive, surface profile, coating, environmental and Perform tests.
- Review & Compile All Field Blasting and Painting Record for Manufacturing Data Report (MDR) or Project Documentation for turn over document to Client.

QC Coating / Welding Inspector Daelim Construction Services Company

Dec,2012-Jan,2014 Saudi Arabia, KSA.

- Responsible in all aspects of welding control including; procedure qualification test (PQT), procedure quality record (PQR)
 and welding procedure standard (WPS). Involve all welding process before, during and after including visual Inspection for
 all kind of Oil and Gas Industries.
- Monitor Inspection progress, review report and documentation and verify, upon completion of work, that all requirement have been met and that the required Quality records have been collated and filed.
- Ensuring coating is practical and in accordance with the specified requirements by preparing or reviewing drawings, specifications, job instructions, and material selection notes etc.
- Witnessing and documenting of painting activities through the preparation of daily inspection Reports, through inspection and documentation.
- Witnessing of tape wrapping and find the pinholes using the holiday detector

QC Welding Inspector Makamin Petroleum Services(Pipeline Services Division) Nov,2011-/Oct,2012 SaudiArabia, KSA.



- Execute the field welding inspection, surveillance and Quality control activities on site, collecting the relevant objective
 proofs, ensuring that all welding operations are executed in accordance with all relevant Codes of Practices and Company
 procedures.
- Controls welding parameters and consumables during installation activities, supervising welding operations, Checks the
 availability and suitability of the filler metal and of the preheating, welding, PWHT, bevels, extent of the repairs made by
 the various welders and taking any corrective actions.
- Witnessing of the welder qualification test (WQT), review certificates of conformity, welding activities both preinstallation, dimensional on fit-up, review welding consumable and material certificates, weld documentation, prepare and
 compile of WQT Manufacturing Data Record. Hand over on completion project, final site inspection procedure,
 monitoring Fit-up / welding and NDE activity on site.
- Clarify any inappropriate or ambiguous issues and resolve quality assurance problems throughout the project execution. Ensure quality assurance and control in conformance with contract requirement. Compile project QA/QC document.

QC Welding Inspector Nesma & Partners Company, KSA Feb,2010-Aug,2011 SaudiArabia, KSA.

 Daily onsite duties include but are not limited to the following activities and responsibilities, Visual examination of spool fit-ups and final welded Inspection.

SRINUVASAN NATARAJAN QA/QC WELDING &COATING INSPECTOR

- Witnessing of the welder qualification test (WQT), review certificates of conformity, welding activities both prefabrication, dimensional on fit-up, review welding consumable and material certificates, weld documentation, prepare of WQT Manufacturing Data Record.
- Check and make sure all Welding root on portable electrode oven (Quiver) are on and good condition, make sure all QC
 Tools which is used are in good condition and all calibrated. Responsible for inspect (visual) of weld-ment after welding
 and request for defect rectification and re-inspect.
- Reviewing and monitoring the welding summary, NDT percentage& clearing the package, as per standards and Project specification release for further activities.
- ensure all of welders during welding activities following the welding procedures specification and sequent used as per
 qualified WPS available and to brief and is intended to demonstrate that welds produced in accordance with a particular
 WPS are capable of providing the properties required for its intended application.

QC Piping Inspector Plus Tech Engineering Pvt. Ltd Sep,2006-Dec,2009 Gujarat, India.



- Monitor marking and cutting activities and inspection joint (Fit-Up and welding).
- Prepare and monitor Punch-list items, ensuring they are resolve prior to testing.
- Verification of materials/consumables as per MTO.
- Stage wise inspection of piping fabrication and erection works with respect to isometric and P&IDs.
- Inspecting the incoming material for damages, dimensions and corrosions and ensure that MTC is available and according to the requirements. Ensure satisfactory identification of material, proper protection of pipe.

Personal Profile

Date of Birth : 03.05.1987 Gender : Male Marital Status : Unmarried

License : Valid (Saudi Arabia)
Language Known : English, Tamil, Hindi

Interests

- I have always aspired to work in an International organization with strong leadership
- enthusiastic and hard working to achieve excellence in work
- Creative and energetic is my style capable to work independently also as a team good inter personal.
- Creative communicative and adaptable

REFERENCES

References are available on request

Declaration

I hereby declare the above details are true to the best of my knowledge. Given an opportunity, I will work to the best satisfaction of the organization.

(N. Srinuvasan)